The MOU is dead, the ceasefire is over,
and technical talks are still occurring.
Which is probably part of the reason
why the price of a barrel of oil has not gone up as high as it has.
This chart here shows a six month time span of the price of Vero oil.
And as you can see, this large bump that started shortly after February
and then has gone down to current levels
is the course of the war and the ceasefire.
During that time, we have severely degraded at Iran's capability
to conduct any kind of military activity whatsoever,
reducing their missiles down to probably about 1,000 at this point.
Their missile launcher capabilities are largely degraded again.
Their navy is largely destroyed,
minus mosquito fleet. Their air force is largely destroyed,
minus a few helicopters.
And the reason why their ground troops haven't been touched
is because they're inept
and not able to be deployed or affect any kind of military situation
in the strait of Hormuz .
Now, also during that time,
the world Learned to adjust and to alter the modes of getting oil,
gas and fertilizer. And so now you see an increase in Brazil production,
in UAE production, in US production,
and a decrease in demand, specifically from China,
by I think a full third.
So China is actually playing their part as well in all of this
to try and get the situation of the Australia hormones, uh,
under control and normalize in The way from the extreme IRGC.
Now, the reason all this kicked off is during the course of the MOU,
the 60 day period, Iran kept trying to institute their toll lanes.
And the US kept saying that that wasn't going to happen.
And every time ships just deviated from Iran's guidance, uh,
they were fired upon. And the US returned, uh,
fire in turn. And for every one ship hit,
we would strike 10 or 20 of their targets.
And in this most recent spat,
Iran struck three ships. And so we struck over 170 targets,
probably upwards of 200. And people keep asking,
how are they able to reconstitute any kind of military firepower whatsoever?
Well, first you should note that how diminished their capability is.
They fire what, one ballistic missile,
a couple drones, none get through.
Maybe one. Uh,
this is a small example of what they used to be able to muster prior to the war.
On top of that,
you have to take into contacts to their large underground facilities
where they housed. And there's plenty of video footage out there to show this.
Housed, uh,
numerous missiles, launchers,
speedboats. And so they are having to dig them out and, uh,
redeploy them. And all this is doing is providing new,
fresh targets for the US to strike.
On top of that,
we ratcheted it up and struck important railway networks out of Iran that's, uh,
supported supply runs from Russia and China.
So We're further isolating Iran's capability of any type of, um, uh,
movement in or out of their country for the purposes of their resources.
And what's also gone largely and reported,
is the Kurdish rebels. Iraq.
Kurdish rebels are causing issues in the mountains
on the border of Iraq and Iran
for IRGC forces as well.
Uh, and so Iran is not in a good place. Now,
the next step is, of course,
Trump's decision. He could easily reinstitute the blockade.
There are two carrier strike groups in the region
with over 20 destroyers of their bouts,
and it's very easy to reinforce that.
In the meantime, some oil is still allowed to escape the strait.
On top of that, there is certain monetary pressures.
Some ships and countries are deciding to go through Iran's Coal Lane
because it's actually cheaper than to pay the overpriced insurance
out of the Lloyds of London.
Um, and so London is also raking in the,
the money. But they've also reached their limit on this as well.
So why people desire certainty and want a return to normal seed.
I don't think they understand what they're asking.
Because what they are asking for is a return to a world
where the IRGC have some sort of power,
influence over the world like they did before, uh,
and maybe even more so if they were given enough time in space.
And I don't understand this desire to allow this to occur.
That world we Had before was first of all, untenable.
We were going to eventually come to this point regardless.
But on top of that, why are you siding with the IRGC?
Why are you deciding with the, uh,
adversaries, the enemies of western society?
All because, uh,
it hurts you. Uh,
there's a little bit more pain at the pump.
Uh, we have not sacrificed what our prior generations have to destroy evil. Uh,
and we're already complaining about it.
And that is part of the reason why this still continues,
because we're not able to put forth this,
the sacrifice that would be necessary to crush this level of evil.
And so we're finding new and innovative ways to contain and change their, um,
mindset. I mean,
look at all we've accomplished without putting a single boot on the ground
or a ship in harm's way. Imagine if we continue to put that pressure campaign on,
and we will. We will continue to degrade their, uh,
military, uh,
capabilities that they decide to dig out of the ground and reconstitute.
And eventually, over time, uh,
this. They will eventually capitulate.
The only way they won't is if you put weak politicians in power.
That's typically the. The thing that, uh,
that causes the US to lose is weak politicians and their inability to, uh,
make the right decision in the moment.